

#### **Imad Aztout**

Mobile: +212 (0) 663 10 69 57 E-mail: <u>Imad\_aztout@hotmail.com</u>

## **SELF DESCRIPTION**

Sales professional. 15 years of experience in IT Solutions sales (hard, soft and services). Management and development of the Channel NW&CA Strategic Marketing, and proven experience in creating and managing profitable businesses. establishing and maintaining relationships with excellent levels of retention and loyalty. Oriented solutions and results.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Hiperdist Alliances. From 01/2019 to current day.

Hiperdist Alliances. (Interdist) is a value-added technology distributor of category-leadingex solutions in Security, Collaboration, Networking and Data Center.

# Country & Sales Manager - Morocco.

I insure that the business meets and exceeds all targets for sales, reseller management and satisfaction across our vendors. Security, Data center, UCC, Networking & Services (Cisco, Imagicle, Netapp, Avaya, Palo Alto, Vmware, Oracle, Commevault, Alibaba Coud ...)

- Responsible for the overall coordination, functional management, and lead sales activities of all Vendors and Sales Teams.
- Establish annual and monthly sales objectives, by team, in coordination with the company's business plan. Supervising, guiding and motivating a team of 10 persons, sales, presales, operations, credits/recovery, logistic and marketing.
- Work with Marketing to ensure consistent lead generation.
- Hire high-performing salespeople according to HR staffing guidelines.
- Manage day-to-day performance of all sales team members and deliver reviews.
- Track sales team metrics and report data to leadership on a regular basis.
- Coach and develop direct reports

#### FINATECH. From 01/2018 to 07/2018.

A major player in the field of energy and digital information and communication technologies, Finatech Group is a leading integrator that offers its private and public customers global solutions and infrastructures from conception, realization, to the maintenance and operation.

Business Development Manager, North, West & Central Africa

- Develop business relationships with Customers, distributors and manufacturers as Huawei, Dell, HP, Lenovo, Cisco, Vmware...
- Manage the entire customer relationship: understand the mapping of the account, advise the client, build a strong and solid partnership and a relationship of trust.
- Ensure a qualification work of the deals: understand the customer's expectations and evaluate the differentiating and competitive criteria in function, develop a commercial strategy.
- Manage all aspects of the value proposition: internal coordination between all the employees involved in the proposal, internal analysis, pricing of the deals, construction of the proposal, oral presentation, coordination and management of the partners...
- Ensure the smooth completion of the contractual closing: closing negotiations and signatures
- Manage a long-term relationship with customers: participate in steering committees, detect new opportunities, and insure customer satisfaction.

## GTI Software & Networking. From 01/2017 to 01/2018.

GTI Software & Networking (Morocco) is a value-added technology distributor of category-leading solutions in Security, Software Mobility, Virtualization, Unified Communication, and Cloud Storage.

# Business Development Manager, North, West & Central Africa

- Develop business relationships with value added resellers & IT Integrators.
- Work with all levels in prospect, from the CEO to the Systems Engineer.
- Commercial management of customer portfolio: Customer visits, negotiation
- Participate in the National & International workshop events.
- Complete business forecasts and activity reports to senior management.
- Prospecting: Recruiting new customers and / or development of Salicru products to existing customers.
- Manage all aspects of the sales process from cold calling to closing.
- Coordination with marketing department to meet the development needs of its customers: contributions, promotions, catalogs, bundles...

#### Westcon Comstor, From 08/2015 to 12/2016.

Westcon Comstor (Westcon Group Inc.) is a value-added technology distributor of category-leading solutions in Security, Collaboration, Networking and Data Center.

## Regional Sales Manager, MAT - Morocco, Algeria & Tunisia.

Ensure that the business meets and exceeds all targets for sales, reseller management and satisfaction across all vendors. Security, Data center, UCC, Networking & Services (Cisco, Solarwinds, Imagicle, Panduit, F5, Netapp, Arbor, Palo Alto, Checkpoint, Juniper, Extreme, Ruckus, Vmware, Kaspersky)

- Responsible for the overall coordination, functional management, and lead sales activities of all Vendors and Sales Teams.
- Establish annual and monthly sales objectives, by team, in coordination with the company's business plan. Supervising, guiding and motivating a team of 15 persons, sales, presales, operations, credits/recovery, logistic and marketing.
- Work with Marketing to ensure consistent lead generation.
- Hire high-performing salespeople according to HR staffing guidelines.
- Manage day-to-day performance of all sales team members and deliver reviews.
- Track sales team metrics and report data to leadership on a regular basis.
- Coach and develop direct reports.

# Westcon Comstor. From 12/2013 to 07/2015.

# Business Manager, MAT - Morocco, Algeria & Tunisia.

- Manage customer accounts and build long term business relationships
- Prospect and recruit new partners in region
- Customer POC / Cisco Advanced technologies solutions
- Analyze customer needs, quote required IT solutions
- Establish strategies that will result in increased sales (both existing and new customers). Penetrate customer accounts at the manager/director levels ...

## Cisco Systems. From 02/2013 to 12/2013.

Cisco is the worldwide leader in IT and networking. American multinational technology, manufactures, and sells networking hardware, telecommunications equipment, and other high-technology services and products.

### Business Manager, West & Central Africa

- Achievement of business (quarterly and annual) targets, in the region, through the management of distributors and partners in the territory.
- Establish direct relationships with partners to maximize revenue opportunities and position Cisco Solutions (Hard, Soft and Service).
- Primary point of contact for Partner for driving sales activity
- Build, drive & close funnel with Partners and distributors
- Responsible for forecasting accuracy and updating SF.com
- Leverage & share available intelligence to drive growth within the Partners (via upsell, cross-sell activities) ...

### INTELCIA Group. From 09/2012 to 02/2013.

A major player in the outsourcing business. Expertise in several business areas: commercial BPO (business process outsourcing), proactive customer relationship management, technical support, customer service, surveys and surveys, and insourcing.

### Team Leader, French market

- Oversee the operational management of the production project Groupon France
- Ensure the daily activity report of my team (15 agents)
- Implement action plans to improve performance (individual and group)
- Make supervisions and evaluations quality assessments
- Conduct regular analysis and establish actions plans to meet agreed targets
- Make sure my team is properly trained and informed about the products and process, check they are applied to achieve qualitative and quantitative targets.
- Administrative follow up (schedules, holidays, plan progress, discipline ...)

#### DELL. From 03/2011 to 06/2012.

PC manufactures, sells to individuals and professionals, it is also present in the markets for enterprise servers, data backup and storage systems and hardware specific to computer network. Dell also offers software and peripherals like printers, digital cameras...

## Sales Manager Online- offline, Consumer, Small & Medium Business, French market

- Team leader, 14 direct reports
- Manage sales of DELL solutions for SMB in French market.
- Participate in the development of online and offline business by implementing all necessary processes to better serve our services for our customers.
- Review weekly and monthly performance with team members (results, problems, measurement objectives, performance improvement action plan to meet objectives...)
- Accountable for the day-to-day sales activities to reach targets: revenue, margin, growth ...
- Understand well the strategy and be able to translate it to an action plan
- Collaborate across the various CSB go-to markets strategies to better serve the customers: Chat, Queue, Outbound & a relationship environment // Direct & Channel
- Ensure resolution of trade issues affecting satisfaction and DELL image
- Recruit new sales representatives if necessary. Etc.

#### DELL. From 09/2009 to 02/2011.

# Technical Sales Rep. / Consultant Server & Storage, Small and Med.Business. French market

- Technical advisor, Design and quote Enterprise Dell solutions (Servers, infrastructures, storage Hardware, Software and Services) servers and backup device associated with storage solutions.
- Provide sales representatives with necessary technical support to enhance detection of enterprise opportunities and respond to technical and financial constraints of the clients first time.
- Establish documents and internal procedure for the validation controls
- Assist the sales force in its negotiations until the conclusion of business.
- Monitor the performance of commercial (individual and group).

#### DELL. From 02/2005 to 09/2009.

# Large Opportunity Rep. /Project manager for Small & Medium Business. Spanish market.

- Responsible for Bid Pipeline management and opportunities detection in an omni channel approach
- Coaches and supports account managers to improve and drive Bid detection including providing feedback and identifying development opportunities & Closing.
- Fixing performance plan and support for commercial Low performers.
- Monitor business performance metrics on a daily basis.
- Build relationships with customers and channel partners based on knowledge of Dells technology as well as the customer business environment
- Effectively articulates Dell Solution approach and Value proposition of Dell as End to End Solution provider to customers and channel partners
- Recommends business solutions considering customer needs and Dell interests.
- Stays informed of current industry trends and applies them to the customer business environment to help solve specific customer challenges in targeted industries
- Makes decision based on an appropriate amount of information/data analysis and brings up new ideas and innovations to be considered for the customer as a trusted advisor

#### DELL. From 09/2004 to 01/2005.

## Sales Engineer for Small & Medium Business. Spanish market

 BSDT: Business Sales Division Transactional, sales of systems Small & Medium Business, Spanish market

### DELL. From 05/2004 to 09/2004.

### Sales Engineer for Small & Medium Business. Spanish market.

• BTB: Behind the box, sales of Software and peripherals for Consumer and Small & Medium Business, Spanish market.

#### **EDUCATION**

**2002-2004:** 2<sup>nd</sup> Cycle, Management at *Institut des Hautes Etudes Economiques et Sociales*, IHEES. Bruxelles - Casablanca.

**2000-2002:** 1st Cycle, Management at *Institut des Hautes Etudes Economiques et Sociales*, IHEES. Brussels - Casablanca.

1999-2000: University Orientation Course, à IES Ávila, Spain.

1998-1999: Bachelor, at Spanish Institute Juan Ramon Jimenez, Casablanca, Morocco.

## **OTHER SKILLS**

Good communication and leadership skills. Ability to manage conflict and resolve complex issues All trainings for "People Management" at Dell. All training for "ESG consultant": Server, Storage, Backup & Software. (Good level) Technology Education (Enterprise Networks, UCC, Data Center & Virtualization) Networking solutions at Cisco. (Good level)

#### **LANGUAGES**

French, English, Spanish, Arabic